# SAMUEL OYEKEYE

## **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

sammyoyekeye70@gmail.com

+37257409011

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sam-oyekeye-a5877a133

https://github.com/Samueloyeks

live:sammyoyekeye70\_1

https://www.samoyekeye.com

## CAREER SUMMARY

Software engineer with strong problem-solving, software development, and system design skills. Well-versed in current technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Extensive experience in creating mobile and web application software using Industry-standard development and deployment practices. Good communication, leadership and collaboration skills. Strategic thinker with a strong drive and passion for developing optimal software solutions that suit user specifications.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

January 2022 - May 2022

https://scoro.com/

Scoro OÜ

Senior Frontend engineer at Scoro, where I was responsible for feature developments and maintenance of Scoro's commercial work management software, Landmark. Worked with micro-frontends and legacy code written in PHP.

#### **Achievements:**

- Completed numerous feature tasks from Score support and customer feedback.
- Created and deployed new features to version release candidates of Landmark

**Technologies used:** 

Vue.ls

GraphQL

JQuery

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

April 2021 - January 2022

Andela/Safaricom PLC https://andela.com/

Software Engineer at Andela Talent Network, where I work on contract under Andela with various companies.

Worked as a lead Front End Engineer at Safaricom, the biggest Telcom in Kenya, https://www.safaricom.co.ke/

#### **Achievements:**

- Successfully led the team that built and deployed Safaricom's first ever self-service portal https://business.safaricom.co.ke/
- Developed and designed both user and admin portals for the self service platform

**Technologies used:** 

React

React Native

Nodejs/Express

#### LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Filmo Realty

January 2020 - July 2021

https://filmorealty.com/

Responsible for leading the product team in management, update and deployment of all the company's in-house web applications and proptech solutions like Vamp and resido for facilities and home management.

#### Achievements:

- Successfully redesigned all company's web application interfaces.
- Provided reliable pro-tech solutions to residential and industrial structures in 12 states all over Nigeria.

**Technologies used:** 

Laravel

VueJS

AdonisJS

## **SKILLS & TOOLS**

#### **Frontend**

Ionic/AngularJS/Angular 7

ReactJS

JavaScript

React-native

Nextis

Vue3

GraphQL

SASS/SCSS

#### **Backend**

Node, IS/Express

Python/Django

Java.

Others

Laravel Git Unit Testing AdonisJS

Sketch

Shopify Google cloud services

## MOST RELEVANT WORK

## SAFARICOM BUSINESS HUB

SHELF DRILLING

SEL-MOBILE

store/apps/details?id=com.selcapitalpartnersmobile.app

FILE NG

**KEGGO** 

https://keggo.ng

VAMPFI

RESIDO

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=resido.filmorealty.com

#### **EDUCATION**

### **B.Sc. in Computer Sciences**

University of Lagos

2014 - 2019

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **Asset and Equity Group**

September 2020 - March 2021

https://assetandequitygroup.com/

Lead software developer at Asset and Equity, an investment banking company which offers financial services as well as government registration and licensing services. I lead the product team to build better service delivery through software.

#### **Achievements:**

- Set up and structured the product team from scratch
- Developed complete user and web platforms for company and business registration and licensing.

Technologies used:

React

React Native

Nodejs/Express

MongoDB

## SOFTWARE TRAINER

#### **Software Development Academy**

January 2021 - Present

https://b2b.sdacademy.pl/

Contract trainer at SDA, a software training academy based in Tallinn Estonia, where I teach basics of Javascript, HTML and CSS, Java as well as core concepts of programming and software development, also training students in programs sponsored by companies like Accenture.

**Technologies used:** 

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

Java

#### LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Mr Taxi

January 2019 - December 2019

https://www.mrtaxinigeria.com/

Led a team of developers to create the Mr Taxi ride-sharing mobile application as a contract job. Implemented all interfaces and core functionalities and deployed the application on android and IOS platforms.

#### **Achievements:**

- Created high-quality design screens for across platforms.
- Utilized Google's Firebase realtime database for finding and tracking drivers and trips.
- Designed API for cab-ordering using USSD technology

**Technologies used:** 

lonic

Heroku

NodeJS

Firebase

MySQL

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Zinospot

March 2016 - February 2018

https://www.zinospot.com/

Worked on various contract products for clients in and out of Nigeria along with a team of developers working under Zinospot based in Tallinn Estonia.

#### **Achievements:**

- Designed and developed various small and medium scale applications for clients
- Developed Keggo, one of Zinospot's products, a fuel-delivery solution.

Technologies used:

Angular

React

React-Native

NodeJS

#### **LANGUAGE**

**English** 

## **INTERESTS**

App design

Workout

Puzzles

**Coding Challenges**